<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Kubru Technology</title>
    <link>https://kubrutech.github.io/</link>
      <atom:link href="https://kubrutech.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <description>Kubru Technology</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>Copyright © Kubru Technology LLC 2020</copyright><lastBuildDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate>
    <image>
      <url>img/map[gravatar:%!s(bool=false) shape:circle]</url>
      <title>Kubru Technology</title>
      <link>https://kubrutech.github.io/</link>
    </image>
    
    <item>
      <title>Secret Files</title>
      <link>https://kubrutech.github.io/blog/0003-disk-file-encryption/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kubrutech.github.io/blog/0003-disk-file-encryption/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;How much personal information is on your computer? Is there anything on your computer that, if it were published on the Internet, would make you uncomfortable or even jeopardize your well-being? If so, then you need to use encryption.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;rule-of-thumb-encrypt-everything&#34;&gt;Rule of thumb: encrypt everything!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are different ways to encrypt your data. At the very least, your data should be encrypted while at rest. That means that if your hard drive or flash drive were stolen, your data would remain unencryptable without providing your secret key. On Mac OS, a built-in feature called Filevault will do the job, and on Windows, the equivalent is BitLocker. Linux distributions often provide a way to perform whole-disk encryption, too. However, if you don&amp;rsquo;t have to enter your password when your computer boots up, you really should enable that, as anyone who attempts to boot your computer would have unfettered access to your data. Also, don&amp;rsquo;t store your encryption key with your encrypted data!&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;safeguard-sensitive-information&#34;&gt;Safeguard sensitive information&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You may think that if your whole disk is encrypted that your data is safe. While whole-disk encryption may protect the data on the drive while it is turned off, anyone with access to the computer (legitimately or not) while it is running will be able to read data on the disk. Backups of your files on your encrypted drive will be decrypted when copied, so your backups won&amp;rsquo;t be encrypted unless you explicitly encrypt them. If a drive is removed from its host computer, there are tools that may be used which may be able to give access to the data depending on the configuration of the host computer.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The threats we are trying to protect against are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Keeping data secret if the physical medium storing it is lost or stolen&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Protecting all non-public information on portable drives due to high probability of being misplaced or left unguarded&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Protecting sensitive data from being accessed by malicious software or other illegitimate means&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I recommend encrypting your sensitive data using a third party mechanism, even if it is stored on an encrypted drive. My requirements for such a tool are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cross platform: Can run on Mac OS, Windows, and Linux, and preferrably on Android and iOS, too.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Portable: I.e., can be run without installing on the host computer. This is very useful when protecting data on removable or portable drives on public computers.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open source: Auditable by anyone.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;veracrypt-to-the-rescue&#34;&gt;VeraCrypt to the rescue!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://veracrypt.fr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; src=&#34;VeraCrypt128x128.png&#34; style=&#34;height: 80px; padding-right:32px&#34; alt=&#34;Link to VereCrpyt Website&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;

&lt;a href=&#34;https://veracrypt.fr&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;VeraCrypt&lt;/a&gt; (and its predecesor, TrueCrypt) meet these requirements and then some. It even offers plausible deniability using hidden volumes, so you can provide a password to an encrypted file containing false or less sensitive data, while the really sensitive data is encrypted a second time inside the first file while not being detectable. That&amp;rsquo;s pretty cool. There are also third-party iOS and Android apps that can manage VeraCrypt files (see the link for Android and iOS support on the VeraCrypt home page).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve used this tool for years to protect sensitive data on a flash drive that I carry on my keychain. Veracrypt, while it can be installed on a host computer, can also be run directly from a flash drive or USB hard drive without being installed, opening up all sorts of oppurtunites for accessing data on any platform.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-does-veracrypt-work&#34;&gt;How does VeraCrypt work?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;VeraCrypt can encrypt an entire drive, one or more partitions on the drive, or it can work with a virtual drive stored as a file on a physical drive. I like to to use VeraCrypt in that last mode, so that&amp;rsquo;s what I will talk about today. If you&amp;rsquo;ve ever worked with disk images in Mac OS, this concept will be very familiar to you.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you launch VeraCrypt, you are given the opportunity to create a new virtual drive or to use an existing one. You simply select the file containing the virtual drive, enter the password and you will have an additional drive available to your system whose contents are encrypted. Since the VeraCrypt executable can be run from a flash drive, this is a very convenient way of storing sensitive information on a flash drive (I carry one on my keychain). If you combine this setup with a live distribution of Linux, you can stick your flash drive in any public computer, boot from it, and have relatively secure access to your sensitive data. And it all fits on a very portable flash drive.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You could also place your virtual drive on a remote system such as a network attached storage (NAS) device. This is probably not optimal for large datasets, but for additional security on small files, it will work just fine. If your use case involves networked storage, check to see what encryption options your networked storage platform offers as it will likely have better performance. Theoretically, you could store your virtual disk on a cloud drive, but performance may not be very good, and I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t store highly sensitive information this way.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;When you are finished using any files on the encrypted virtual drive, simply unmount the virtual drive. (Use the eject command on Mac OS or Windows.). Remember to do this &lt;i&gt;before&lt;/i&gt; disconnecting any removable drives to avoid data corruption. I recommend disabling write caching for removable drives, if your system has such a setting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;caveats&#34;&gt;Caveats&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Backups for encrypted drives may require some extra attention. The drive, volume, or virtual disk must be unlocked before you can copy files from it to another location, and this may complicate your existing backup mechanisms. If you use cloning software to copy your entire disk, you will generally be okay, though sometimes it may not be possbile to backup disks with encrypted partitions. I suggest you read the documentation for the disk encryption software you will use as well as the backup software you will use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Don&amp;rsquo;t lose your encryption key! If you can&amp;rsquo;t find or recover your key, you will be unable to access your encrypted data, so make sure to store your encryption key in a safe place. How safe of a place depends on the consequences of your data being accessed by the wrong person, so think carefully about your threats and the risks associated with them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One last note of advice: When creating an encrypted volume, Use a strong password that is not&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;So, learn about the built-in encryption mechanisms that ship with your operating system and if they don&amp;rsquo;t meet your needs, look into third party solutions&amp;ndash;there are many. VeraCrypt is a tried and true free and open source solution that has worked well for me for a long time, and may very well be adequate for your needs, too.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Covering My Tracks</title>
      <link>https://kubrutech.github.io/blog/0002-private-browsing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kubrutech.github.io/blog/0002-private-browsing/</guid>
      <description>&lt;h2 id=&#34;you-can-run-but-you-cant-hide&#34;&gt;You can run, but you can&amp;rsquo;t hide!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve used ad-blockers for a long time, but not for the reason you may think. I have lived in places where unmetered Internet&amp;ndash;or any Internet service at all&amp;ndash;is hard to get. I lived for years on expensive metered cellular data plans, so it was not in my best interest to pay for downloading all the ads that appeared on almost evey website I visited. On top of the cost, downloading those ads cost me time because my connections were usually slow.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Once I got unmetered and slightly faster Internet access, I kept using the ad-blockers, but I felt guilty. Content creators often depend on ad revenue for their livelihood, and many sites reminded me of that fact every time I visited them. On the other hand, advertisements can contain malicious software and they track my every move on the web.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;how-are-ads-and-browsing-tracking-a-threat-to-me&#34;&gt;How are ads and browsing tracking a threat to me?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The primary threats I am trying to avoid when using a web browser are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Downloading of malicious software such as ransomware and cryptominers without my express permission&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fingerprinting that can be used to adjust the prices I see when shopping online among other nefarious purposes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Search engines using my browsing habits to respond to queries with links I&amp;rsquo;m more likely to follow than with links that have the information I&amp;rsquo;m actually looking for&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Disclosure of information about me without my consent&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;These are all very real threats that I&amp;rsquo;ve personally experienced in the past. Ads are the primary means (though there are other ways) for delivering malware and trackers. Google analytics and other site measurement tools are another way your browsing activity is tracked. (You might like to know that Google analytics is not used on this website.) The collected data often gets passed around and as the end user, you have very little control of this information dissemination except to block it outright.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-search-begins&#34;&gt;The search begins&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There has to be a solution to this tracking problem. So I went searching for the ultimate browser/plugin combination that would meet all of my requirements, which are:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cross platform: runs on Mac, Windows, Linux, iOS, and Android&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Blocks all trackers&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;And secondarily:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Allows me to sync my bookmarks between devices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compensates content creators even when ads are blocked&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Mainstream (used by many people), regularly updated.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It turns out there are several that meet the first two requirements. My instinct told me to check out Firefox. I&amp;rsquo;ve heard about TOR and how it helps you to become anonymous on the Web, so I want to at least have that tool in my arsenal. And while I&amp;rsquo;m not a fan of Chrome, I&amp;rsquo;ve heard about Brave which is based on Chromium and becoming more popular. There are others, I know, but remember, I want a mainstream browser, too.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-independent-privacy-browser-mozilla-firefox&#34;&gt;The independent privacy browser: Mozilla Firefox&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mozilla.org/en-US/exp/firefox/new&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; src=&#34;Fx-Browser-icon-fullColor-128.png&#34; style=&#34;width:128px;padding-right:32px;&#34; alt=&#34;Download Firefox&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
Mozilla 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.mozilla.org/firefox/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Firefox&lt;/a&gt; is a great open source, cross platform browser with a rich add-on ecosystem. Lately, Firefox has made great strides in enhancing privacy, blocking many kinds of trackers and ads&amp;ndash;all without third-party extensions. I was surprised to learn that I no longer needed a plugin to block ads&amp;ndash;this is awesome news! It blocks fingerprinting requests from sites known to use fingerprinting techniques. (With fingerprinting, it is possible to track a web user without cookies even when other tracking mechanisms are blocked.) It can sync between devices, too. Mozilla has a small suite of privacy based tools that I&amp;rsquo;m sure I will explore in the future. In fact the only thing lacking from Firefox is a way to compensate content creators after blocking their ads. I highly recommend Firefox to anyone who wants an open source, cross platform browser and for those who just don&amp;rsquo;t like Chromium-based browsers. For what it&amp;rsquo;s worth, Firefox did seem to use less RAM on my Windows laptop than Brave.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;the-anonymous-browser-tor-browser&#34;&gt;The anonymous browser: TOR Browser&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/download&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; src=&#34;tor-onion.png&#34; style=&#34;width:128px;padding-right:32px&#34; alt=&#34;Download TOR Browser&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;  
&lt;a href=&#34;https://www.torproject.org/&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;TOR Browser&lt;/a&gt; uses the TOR network to provide a relatively high level of anonymity. It tunnels your browsing traffic through multiple internet hosts, the actual source of the requests. Cookies are automatically deleted after every session. All TOR browsers have the same fingerprint rendering fingerprinting techniques less effective. Due to the latency and bandwidth limitations when using TOR, I wouldn&amp;rsquo;t want to use it as my everyday browser&amp;ndash;only when truly needed. If you live in a country where censorship is prevalent and you almost always need TOR capabilities, TOR Browser may be an appropriate choice. But for me, living in the United States, it seems a little too niche. I don&amp;rsquo;t think I need that much privacy&amp;ndash;at least not right now. Note that TOR Browser is not available for iOS at this time though it is available for Windows, Linux, Mac OS, and Android.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;my-new-favorite-private-browser-brave&#34;&gt;My new favorite private browser: Brave!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href=&#34;https://brave.com/kub418&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34;&gt;&lt;img align=&#34;left&#34; src=&#34;brave-lion.png&#34; style=&#34;width:128px; padding-right:32px&#34; alt=&#34;Download Brave Browser&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;
The 
&lt;a href=&#34;https://brave.com/kub418&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;Brave Browser&lt;/a&gt; simply blew me away. It&amp;rsquo;s fully compatible with Chrome which means if a site works in Chrome (a very popular browser), it should work in Brave. Chrome extensions work in Brave. I was surprised to find that I could open a TOR browsing tab and gain some anonymity when I needed to, a real benefit in my book. Brave blocks every ad on every website that I&amp;rsquo;ve visited over the last couple of months, and also stops most types of fingerprinting, and the Brave team is continually working on improved anti-fingerprinting techniques. The Brave browser is available on every major platform and lets me sync across devices. Brave has 14 million users and is growing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;
&lt;a href=&#34;https://brave.com/kub418&#34; title=&#34;Download Brave Browser&#34; target=&#34;_blank&#34; rel=&#34;noopener&#34;&gt;&lt;img src=&#34;./ad336x280-standard.png&#34; alt=&#34;&#34;&gt;&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What I really like is how Brave offers an opt-in system of rewards for viewing ads that don&amp;rsquo;t track you and that are much less obtrusive than conventional ads seen on the Internet. The advertiser doesn&amp;rsquo;t know anything about you except that their ad was viewed. Ads appear as system notifications, so a small message pops up and eventually disappears and you get paid. Ads are typically not shown when you are actively using your computer. I usually see them after I&amp;rsquo;ve stepped away from my computer and then come back and move the mouse. Sometimes I see an ad when I switch from another application back to the Brave browser. I like that the ads never interfere with what I&amp;rsquo;m doing. If you click on the notification, you get to learn more about the product or service being advertised. It is possible to use your rewards to tip content creators and you can even schedule tips to be made monthly. Or, using the auto-contribute feature, you can let Brave automatically pay content creators based on how often you visit a website. If you&amp;rsquo;d rather keep the rewards, you can redeem them for cash or gift cards, but that requires disclosing personal information to one or more third parties. I&amp;rsquo;m happy that I no longer feel guilty blocking those annoying and malicious ads, and that content creators in the know can still be compensated.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;(Full disclosure: I have registered as a Brave content creator and will be rewarded if you download the Brave Browser using the links on this page. Within the Brave browser, you may tip me by clicking on the triangle at the right of the address bar when visiting the KubruTech website.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;conclusion&#34;&gt;Conclusion&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In summary, you can&amp;rsquo;t go wrong with either Brave or Firefox. Brave is a drop-in replacement for Chrome and Firefox has always been a very good alternative to the browser that ships with your operating system of choice. If it&amp;rsquo;s important to you, like it is for me, that content creators be compensated for their work, Brave offers an innovative means for compensating producers while protecting consumers. For most users, I believe Brave is the best browser available right now.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>My Life Is An Open (Face)Book</title>
      <link>https://kubrutech.github.io/blog/0001-my-life-is-an-open-book/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 May 2020 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://kubrutech.github.io/blog/0001-my-life-is-an-open-book/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;When the Internet was young and used mostly at research institutions and universities, there was a widespread notion that everything should be freely shared. I believe the open source movement has brought many benefits to society, but I no longer believe that all information should be publicly available. Access to certain information should be restricted if the owner of that information desires it.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;There are different reasons why access to certain information should be restricted. It could be that making it public would cause financial harm to certain individuals. Identity theft can make many common financial tasks a real chore, and repairing a reputation is not always easy or inexpensive. Other data, if made publicly available, could put personal safety in jeopardy. Intimate knowledge of a person&amp;rsquo;s personal life could make it easier for a malicious individual to defraud them, by enabling the fraudster to more easily build a false sense of trust with their target.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;why-do-so-many-people-like-facebook&#34;&gt;Why do so many people like Facebook?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I first signed up for Facebook when a friend wanted to share pictures of her newborn with me. For a while facebook was actually somewhat useful, although I still don&amp;rsquo;t understand why I would have ever wanted to &amp;ldquo;poke&amp;rdquo; someone. Eventually, I made lots of &amp;ldquo;friends&amp;rdquo; on facebook, and the vast majority of them post unoriginal content or other drivel and now the whole experience has been reduced to a huge waste of time. Too many people posting too much information that, I think, should just be kept private. Do I really care what everyone eats at every meal? And thank you, but I can find videos I actually want to watch on YouTube without the help of my friends. The really dastardly thing about Facebook, though, is that they have become an expert at identifying who you truly are&amp;ndash;not just by what you reveal to them, but by what those you&amp;rsquo;ve identified as friends reveal about you. It is almost impossible to hide your personal information from Facebook, even if you don&amp;rsquo;t use it yourself, as their trackers are all over the web. But there are ways and we&amp;rsquo;ll talk about them in the future.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;did-you-really-just-say-that&#34;&gt;Did you really just say that?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;What got me the most was the announcements on Facebook of where people were going, and how long they&amp;rsquo;d be gone. The first thing that crossed my mind was that anyone who followed their Facebook &amp;ldquo;feed&amp;rdquo; now knew the best time to burglarize someone&amp;rsquo;s house. Often these posts were viewable by everyone in the world! Or if one were the stalking type, the &amp;ldquo;feed&amp;rdquo; contained enough information to follow people around through their daily routines. I found it disturbing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;so-what-is-privacy-anyway&#34;&gt;So what is privacy anyway?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Internet privacy is the ability to restrict knowledge of certain information to certain people. Put another way, in the context of the Internet, privacy is to have control over your personal information and it&amp;rsquo;s distribution. When you think about it, maintaining control over your personal information online can be more difficult than you might think. Almost every website with a login asks for information that, if it weren&amp;rsquo;t properly controlled, could be detrimental to the user&amp;rsquo;s well-being. Most websites take information without explicitly asking for it. For example, location is derived from IP address and fingerprints associate you with information gathered at other websites. This information is then passed around to various third parties in order for the site owner to make a little money. It seems that it&amp;rsquo;s almost impossible to control the distribution of personal information without completely opting-out of modern society. That&amp;rsquo;s what this blog is about&amp;ndash;maintaining some privacy while still enjoying the conveniences of the Internet and modern digital technologies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;privacy-is-not-anonymity&#34;&gt;Privacy is not anonymity&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Many people online seem to equate privacy with anonymity. It may be true that by remaining anonymous, one would refrain from divulging personal information. But I believe complete anonymity to be a cowardly approach. I find a person or business without a reputation untrustworthy. Trust must be earned, so a certain amount of information must be made public in order to gain respect and trust. To have privacy on the Internet is to be able to control what aspects of your life are public and which are not. In future blog posts, we&amp;rsquo;ll touch on ways to become anonymous when you need or want to. (Tip: it&amp;rsquo;s virtually impossible to be anonymous on a mobile phone. And it takes effort, usually a lot of effort, to become truly anonymous online.)&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;privacy-is-not-security&#34;&gt;Privacy is not security&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Some people think privacy is synonymous with security. Privacy and security are related, but they are not nearly the same. You could build a house of bullet-proof glass and you may be secure inside it, but everything you do will be visible to anyone passing by on the street. However, security plays an important role in restricting access to personal information. We&amp;rsquo;ll talk about security in future blog posts when we talk about different ways to restrict access to personal information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;what-needs-to-be-kept-private&#34;&gt;What needs to be kept private?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Determining which personal information must be kept private is a personal choice. Each person must examine the threats to their privacy along with the probability and severity of the consequences of a breach and decide how to deal with those risks. Mitigation costs will also play a role in these decisions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Certain classes of people (e.g., journalists, dissidents, criminals, and others) may have very high costs (to personal or other liberties, reputation, etc.) associated with the leaking of certain information such as location or confidential communications to untrusted parties with big pocketbooks, like governments, mobs, or well-funded terrorist organizations. These types of people must take extreme measures to keep certain information private, often at great inconvenience or cost. For some people, simply using a celluar telephone may not be an option because the phone all by itself would divulge too much information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The following are some types of personal information to which I want to control access:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Information that could be used to commit identiy theft: Date of birth, mother&amp;rsquo;s maiden name, driver license number, answers to security questions, etc.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;My real-time location (past location is not as important unless it reveals places I might frequently be found or that I pass by and can be easily observed)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Health records and information, and I&amp;rsquo;ll include fitness information here, too, since that can be used to deduce general health level. While illegal in many areas, knowledge of certain health conditions could still dissuade employers from hiring me, or insurers from wanting to insure me.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Financial information: This includes salary, account balances, asset details, etc. 
There are ligitimate cases where this information should be shared, but I must be able to control when and with whom this information is shared and be reasonably assured that those holding custody of this information are competent to protect it.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I find it cost-prohibitive (either in dollars, opportunity, or convenience) to try to hide from a government, and at least currently, don&amp;rsquo;t have anything to hide from them. It is important to realize that all Internet traffic is being monitored, that information is being recorded long-term and that information might be used to your disadvantage in the future. So it&amp;rsquo;s important to be careful about what personal information you share, with whom you share it, and to consider the tustworthiness of the entities holding your personal information.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id=&#34;where-to-from-here&#34;&gt;Where to from here?&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;In future posts, I&amp;rsquo;ll talk about things I do to protect the information I want to keep private. It will be an interesting and educational journey for sure, and I invite you to follow along and learn with me.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
